Stanislav Starishko

Glasgow, UK, G72 8PG | WhatsApp/Tel: 07387914778 | Email: starishko.s@gmail.com

Web: https://github.com/StanStarishko/Portfolio | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/starishko/

Permit: Category B | **Legally authorized to work** in the UK

Personal Statement:

Motivated results-driven professional with years of experience, recognised for assessing operational needs, and developing solutions to save costs, improve revenues and drive customer satisfaction. Resourceful, well-organised with excellent leadership and team-building record. Passionate Developer with experience in data accuracy, management. Independent problem-solver focused on customer service, product development. Works well under tight deadlines.

Technical Skills:

- Programming Languages: 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce), T-SQL, Java (Collections, Lambda Expressions), Python (Flask, Pandas, NumPy, Lambda Expressions), JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++
- Development Tools & Environments: Delivering complex (ERP) enterprise level systems, Writing secure and high-quality code, Full Life Cycle and Decisions Architecture, Object-Oriented (OOP), Modular Programming, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), MVC, SOLID, QA MT/AT, Unit Testing, Test Driven Development (TDD), BDD, Design of architecture IT products, services and solutions, AWS, Lambda, S3, APIs, Jira, Trello, Data and system analyst
- Databases: MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, and Time, Team, Product, Project, and Crisis Management

Key Skills:

- Enthusiastic up for challenge
- Analytical and Outside The Box Thinking
 Crisis Resolution
- Excellent Team Collaboration
- Passionate about software
- Attention to Detail
- Team Productivity Enhancement
- Business Process Understanding
- Process Modernization

Work History:

Glasgow Film Theatre, UK

08/2023 - Current

Volunteer-Customer Assistant

- Managed over 50 customer asks per day, checked tickets, cleaned up after show
- Reached English skills from A1 to B1 Level

EVOS Good Food, Uzbekistan

09/2021 - 02/2022

Director of Digital Transformation

- Established ERP systems increased accounting and finance productivity by 30%
- · Contributed to innovative solutions implementation of timekeeping facial recognition by Hik-Vision into HRsystem, ERP enhancing HR processes by 80% within 2.5 months
- Introduced steps to halt technological debt growth within two months

Freelance, Ukraine 11/2019 - 08/2021

Software Engineer

- Developed software modules to improve financial reporting speed to 25%
- Debugged and modified software components to fix faults

EVA Retail, Ukraine 10/2018 - 11/2019

Head Software Department

- Performed adoption of innovative methodologies, including SBS feedback, hybrid Agile, Scrum, CorpScrum, Prince2, Waterfall approach, resulting in 20% increase in team productivity
- Successfully managed over 10 long-term projects (each 1-3 years), one of key ones being payment calendar
- Executed more than 20 short-term projects (each up to 6 months) to conclusion, consistently meeting all deadlines
- Developed strategy plan to redeveloped support software for 900+ retail outlets, 3500+ users, achieving efficiency improvement of 10%
- Developed, rolled-out of complex enterprise-level systems (ERP), resulting in 10% uplift in productivity for accounting, finance departments
- Deployed strategic framework successfully stopped growth of company's technological debt within 4 month

Re-entry from Junior 1C8 Developer to Head of Software Department

- Solved problems in 280 1C databases on MSSQL, reduced update time by 98%, from 2.5 months to 3-5 days
- Established transformative initiative skyrocketed support team's efficiency by impressive 80%
- Overcame seemed insurmountable challenges within remarkable 2 weeks, and outpaced outsourcing projections set for 8 month timeframe
- Reduction of exchange time from 8-14 hours to 2-5 minutes by deployed high-speed synchronization system for 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce), with Office Tools
- Performed, beginning from scratch, seamless execution comprehensive automation plan for manufacturing within ambitious 10-month timeline

Company Adeon Franchising 1C, Ukraine

02/2007 - 03/2014

Co-owner/CEO

• Successfully delivered 12+ long-term projects within specified timelines, ranging from 8 to 18 months, utilising 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce), T-SQL, MSSQL

Retail and Logistic Companies, Ukraine

10/1991 - 02/2007

- **Software Developer**
 - In 2003, rapid effectively, for one month, retrained to 1C developer (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce)
 - Performed software development excellence for over decade from 1991 to 2003, established proficiency in Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++

Education and Training:

PDA Cyber Resilience	SCQF8	Code Division, futureCoders	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
Cyber Engineers	CyberOps Associate	Cisco Networking Academy	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
PDA Software Development	SCQF7	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	08/2023 - 11/2023
NPA Software Development	SCQF6	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	04/2023 - 07/2023
NQ Access to Business Administration, Accounting and IT	SCQF4	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	01/2023 - 06/2023
Python	Fundamental	DataCamp	USA	11/2022 - 03/2023
New strategic thinking. Selection Management	Advanced	EVA Academy, Arkadiy Tsuker	Ukraine	05/2019 - 05/2019
Project Management by Agile, Scrum and Kanban	Advanced	EVA Academy	Ukraine	11/2018 - 04/2019
Corporate course of business changes and transformation	МВА	Institute of Adizes, Ukrainian Office	USA	02/2018 - 09/2018
Programming for Computing Devices and Automated Systems	BTEC, SCQF7	Automation and Telemechan College	Ukraine	09/1990 - 03/1993

Languages: English - Intermediate, Ukrainian – Native, Russian - Native

Hobbies & Interests: Traveling, exploring new technologies, personal development